Rohit Roy

Backend Developer

Personal Info

Address

Bangalore, India

Phone

+91-7022374158

E-mail

rohit7roy@gmail.com

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/rohit--roy

GitHub

www.github.com/rohit5roy

Skype rohit5roy

Programming Languages

JAVA JavaScript NoSQL, SQL HTML5, CSS

Web Technologies

Microservices Architecture

Spring Boot Spring Cloud NodeJS

React Js

Docker

Kafka Message Queue AWS Components

Mobile Technologies

Android SDK

Tools

Intellij IDEA Android Studio IDE GIT RoboMongo

Database

MySQL MongoDB SQLite

Cloud Tools

Amazon Web Services Linode

Business Skills

Communication Leadership Creativity Experienced professional with more than 10 years of experience as a Software Engineer in design and development of Android applications, Web Applications and IT services. In depth know-how and hands-on with 10+ "Full Mobile and Web Application Development Life Cycle Projects" in wide variety of device resolutions and SDK versions. Demonstrated excellent skill set in Android, JAVA, MEAN stack, Spring boot and Microservices architecture using Cloud components & infrastructure

Experience

08/2023 present

Staff Software Engineer

Bazaarvoice Technologies

- Collaborated with Product managers to fulfill roadmaps and goals.
- Lead and designed distributed system that handle high traffic and pressure.
- Responsible for product, with more than 15K clients (Top merchants/brands).
- Lead the team to develop Cloud native apps using Spring cloud, RDS, and ECS.
- Designed and Developed Web Application using Javascript frameworks.
- Worked with micro services architecture using Spring Cloud, Kubernetes and Serverless cloud components like AWS Lambda.
- CICD via GitHub Actions along with observability via Graphana/Datadog.

05/2022 -07/2023 **SDE-3** Sahai AI

- Gathered and evaluated requirements to create technology roadmaps and goals.
- Lead the team to develop Cloud native apps using Spring cloud, RDS, and Docker.
- Designed and Developed Web Application using Javascript frameworks.
- Worked with micro services architecture using Spring Cloud, Kubernetes and Serverless cloud components like AWS Lambda.

04/2021 -11/2021 SDE-2

Apptio

- Gathered and evaluated requirements to create technology roadmaps and goals.
- Developed Secure Web App using Spring boot, React JS and MySQL.
- Updated the system to use the AWS Aurora for more scalability and resilience.

08/2019 -

10/2017 -

08/2019

Technical Lead

04/2021 Trianz Holdings & ESecure Solutions

- Lead the team and developed Secure Web App using Spring boot, React JS and MySQL.
- Designed and Developed Web Application using Javascript frameworks.
- Hands-on with micro services architecture using Spring Cloud and AWS.

Senior Software Engineer

Milvik Technologies

Analyzed and evaluated requirements to create technology roadmaps and goals.

- Lead the team and developed Secure Web App using Spring boot, JSP and MySQL.
- Designed and Developed Web Application using Javascript frameworks.
- Hands-on with micro services architecture using Spring Cloud and AWS.
- Handling multiple markets and communicating with the stakeholders.

Initial Experience in Start-Ups

- Worked in Instano Technologies as an Android Developer.
- Worked in Sopnop Technologies as Software Engineer.
- Served in Mphasis Pvt. Ltd. as a Systems Engineer.
- Lead and Developed Secure Web App using MongoDB, ExpressJs, AngularJs and NodeJs.
- Designed and Developed Android Application in Java with REST APIs interaction.
- In depth Facebook SDK and Google Maps API integration for various types of synchronizations.

09/2014 -09/2017

- Designed and Developed Android Application in Java with Smack API for server interaction.
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Developed test scenarios; conducted unit-level testing; Robotium for black box testing.}$
- Hand on assembling, handling and testing the physical servers and the data racks.

Education

07/2010 -06/2014 **Dehradun Institute of Technology**

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering.

Impact Projects

08/2017 -07/2019

Doctor Portal

Doctor Portal is a platform to track the life cycle of a consultation apart from providing online/tele consultations to the customers. Doctor Portal empowers the Agents/App to discover the correct customer then allows them to get a Doctor Consultation which then results to e-prescription or a follow up consultation. Currently the application is live in 8 markets, with Bangladesh having near to 3 million customers and around a 500K consultations provided in the year (2018-19), other markets include Ghana, Pakistan, Paraguay, Egypt, Malaysia, Sri Lanka and Indonesia.